Guide to the Mabel Dodge Luhan Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
The final, untitled scrapbook, dating from roughly 1914-28, contains both clippings and writings. There are clippings on Luhan, various friends, and Native American Indians, including 33 brief newspaper articles by Luhan. Most articles in this volume duplicate articles found in "Misc. Vol. 1," however there are a few articles unique to each volume. In addition to the clippings, there are several typescript manuscripts.
Series V, Personal Papers, housed in boxes 99-101, is organized into ten subseries: Artwork, Clippings, Diaries, Financial and Legal Records, Invitations and Announcements, John Evans Papers, Medical Records, Postcards, Printed Ephemera, and Other. The Artwork subseries includes drawings by D. H. Lawrence and Maurice Sterne, and paintings by Marsden Hartley, Stephen Haweis, Gisella Lacher, and Max Weber. The Clippings subseries brings together all loose clippings that deal with or at least mention Luhan. Clippings date from 1912-59 and include common subgroups for Brief Mentions, General Interest articles, and Literary References. The Diaries and Medical Records appear to contain documents of Luhan's analysis with Dr. Smith Ely Jelliffe.
Series VI, Subject Files, housed in box 102, is organized into two subseries: People and Topics. The files consist chiefly of clippings on friends and family.
Oversize material, housed in boxes 103-107, includes items from Series I-III and Series V-VI. Restricted Papers, Restricted Fragile Papers, and Restricted Fragile Oversize are housed in boxes 108, 109-110, and 111-112 respectively.
American literature -- 20th Century; Art, Modern -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Indians of North America -- New Mexico; Labor -- United States; Psychoanalysis; Florence (Italy); New York (N.Y.); Taos (N.M.); Autobiographies (documents); Cabinet photographs; Negatives; Photographic prints; Scrapbooks; Tintypes (prints); Authors; Studio portraits; Abbe, James Edward, 1883-1973; Adams, Ansel, 1902-1984; Boyce, Neith, 1872-1951; Collier, John, 1884-1968; Evans, John, 1902-; Gilpin, Laura; Hapgood, Hutchins, 1869-1944; Hartley, Marsden, 1877-1943; Jelliffe, Smith Ely, 1866-1945; Jones, Robert Edmond, 1887-1954; Knee, Ernest, 1907-1982; Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert), 1885-1930; Lawrence, Frieda, 1879-1956; Luhan, Mabel Dodge, 1879-1962; O'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986; Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946; Stein, Leo, 1872-1947; Sterne, Maurice, 1878-1957; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; Weston, Edward, 1886-1958; Collier family; Armory Show ( 1913 New York, N.Y.)
- Correspondence, 1905-1954; Series I; 17.31; (42 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is organized into two subseries: General Correspondence and Third Party Correspondence.
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - "A" General, 1914-59, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
      Includes copy of letter from Gavin Arthur to Mrs. Turnbull Wood
    - Abbott, Leonard [Dalton?], 1915-23, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Abel, Walter, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Abend, Hallet
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Bachus, Lucy Reynolds, Box 2, folder 59
    - Aberle, Sophie D.
      See: Native American Indian material, Box 26, folders 745-752
    - Acosta, Mercedes de, 1936, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Acton, Arthur, 1914-52, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9-12)
      Includes note from MDL and letter from William Acton
    - Acton, Harold, 1953 Mar 29 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Adams, Ansel, 1929-48, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Includes carbons of letters from Adams to Robert Thomas Hardy and Alfred Harcourt
    - Adams, Virginia, 1930, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14a)
    - Adler, Felix, 1914 Jan 2 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Adrian, Gilbert, 1934-59, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16-18)
      Includes enclosure from DeWitt B. Lucas
    - Aisen, Maurice, 1925, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Akins, Zoë, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Alan Swallow (Firm), 1953 Mar 9 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      See also: Sage Books, Box 31, folder 884
    - Albertson, Hazel
      See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters to Accompany Volume VI of Intimate Memories" (leaves 318-340), Box 52, folder 1406
    - The Albuquerque Tribune, 1936-37 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Includes carbon from MDL and letter from Robert Scripps to MDL
    - Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1925-53 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      See also: Scrapbooks, "Lawrence," Box 87, folder 2256
      See also: Scrapbooks, "Lawrence Vol. II," Box 88, folder 2257
    - The American Caravan, 1926-30 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      See also: Rosenfeld, Paul, Box 30, folder 870
    - American Indian Defense Association, 1925 Apr 22 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - American Women's War Relief Fund, 1915 Jan 8 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Anderson, Lizzie, 1952-53 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Angell, Hildegarde, 1924, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Angulo, Guimar de, 1951 Sep 8 (Box 1, Folder 28a)
    - Angulo, Jaime de, 1923-36, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 29-32)
      Includes photograph
    - Angulo, Nancy de, 1925-33, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 33)
      See also: Angulo, Guimar de, Box 1, folder 28a
    - Archuleto, Antonio (nephew-in-law), 1923-40, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 34-36)
    - Archuleto, John (brother-in-law), 1945 Jan 1 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Armijo, Eduardo, 1927-45 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Armitage, Merle, 1946 Jul 26 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Arnold, Elliott, 1953 Oct 31 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - The Arts, 1924-25 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Asquith, Anthony, 1925 Dec 12 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Associated Press, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Association of American Painters and Sculptors, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Atherton, Gertrude, 1935, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Atwood, Stella M., 1922-28 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Auner, Frances Nate, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      Includes copy of poem by Charles Beghtol
    - Austin, Mary Hunter, 1920-33, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 48-51)
      Includes note from MDL on verso of letter dated "1930 May 6" and drawing
    - "B" General, 1913-54, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 52-58)
      Includes poems by Lela Dalton Bailey and photographs
    - Bachus, Lucy Reynolds, 1923, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 59)
      Includes enclosures
    - Baker, George P., 1929 Aug 3 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Baldwin, Faith, 1935, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Barker, S. Omar, 1939 Feb 21 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Barnes, Albert C. (Albert Coombs), 1930 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Barnes, Carman, 1938-42, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 64-65)
    - Barnes, Djuna, 1914 Feb 14 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Barnes, Nellie, 1938, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Barnhart, Harry, [1924-25?] (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Bartlett, Frank S., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Beach, Mary B., 1936-37 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Beatty, Bessie, 1945 Feb 8 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Becker, Charlotte, 1927-37, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 72)
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters of John and Lucy Collier 1913-17" (leaf 394), Box 51, folder 1405
    - Beckett, Luman, 1935-42 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Bell, Galt, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Bender, Albert M., 1935-36 (Box 3, Folder 75)
      See also: Scrapbooks, "European Experiences," Box 84, folder 2253
    - Benedict, Wallace, 1915-16, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Bennett, Melba, 1938-44, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Bergson, H.[enri?]
      See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters from Hutchins & Neith Hapgood..." (leaf 299), Box 51, folder 1404
    - Berkman, Alexander, 1913-14, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 78)
      Includes letter from MDL
    - Bermann, Richard A., 1937, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 79)
      See also: Scrapbooks, "Winter in Taos," Box 97, folder 2266
    - Berninghaus, Oscar E. (Oscar Edmund), 1947-51 (Box 3, Folder 80)
      See also: Scrapbooks, "History of Taos & Its Artists," Box 54, folder 2254
    - Bird, Carol, 1938-40, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Birnbaum, Martin, 1916 Feb (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Bizardel, Yvon, 1947-48 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Blackwater Camp, [1922?] (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Blanche, Jacques-Emile, 1911-33, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 85)
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Miscel[l]aneous Letters (1915 & 1916)" (leaf 53), Box 53, folder 1408
    - Blumenschein, [Ernest Leonard?], 1925-48 (Box 3, Folder 86)
      Includes letter from Mary Blumenschein
    - Bohn, Wm. E. (William Edward)
      See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters from Hutchins & Neith Hapgood..." (leaf 312), Box 51, folder 1404
    - Boni & Liveright, 1919 Oct 7 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Borély, Jules, 1928, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Bourgeois, Stephan, 1916-45 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Boyce, Neith, 1913-41, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 90-98)
      Includes drawings by Maurice Sterne on verso of letter dated "1918" and notes from Hutchins Hapgood
      See also: Hapgood, Hutchins, Box 16, folders 448-460
    - Boyce, Neith, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Boyd, Madeleine, 1940 Jan 11 (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Boyesen, Bayard, 1913-27, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 101-102)
      Includes letter from Auril Boyesen and poem
    - Boyle, Kay, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Bradley, Florence
      See: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Miscel[l]aneous Letters 1914" (leaves 311-34), Box 52, folder 1407
    - Bragdon, Claude Fayette, 1934-45, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Brenner, Anita, 1933 Jan 8 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Brett, Dorothy, 1926-42 (Box 4, Folder 106-114)
      Includes letter from MDL and clipping
    - Brett, Dorothy, 1943-54, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 115-120)
    - Briffault, Robert, 1938 Jan 6 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Brill, A. A. (Abraham Arden), 1916-44, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 122-126)
      Includes notes from MDL to Brill on "July 28, 1938" letter from Curtis Brown and "July 20th" letter from Neysa
    - Brill, Edmund, 1939-51 (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Brill, Rose, 1937-53, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Brinig, Myron, 1934-53, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 129-133)
    - Brisbane, Arthur, 1912-37, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 134-138)
      Includes letters from MDL and enclosures from M. Goddard and Will H. Hays
    - Brisbane, Elinor, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 139)
    - Brisbane, Phoebe, 1913-46, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 140)
    - Bromfield, Louis, 1943, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 141)
    - [Brooke?], Rupert, 1914 May 25 (Box 5, Folder 142)
    - Brundage, Frances, 1925, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - Bryant, Louise, 1926, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - Buffalo Fine Arts Academy
      See: Quinton, Cornelia Sage, Box 28, folder 824
    - Bull, Nina, 1912-42, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 145-153)
      Includes letters from MDL
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters to Accompany Volume VI of Intimate Memories" (leaf 373), Box 51, folder 1405
    - Bull, Nina, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 154-155)
    - Burgess, Gelett, 1914 Apr 7 (Box 5, Folder 156)
    - Burlin, Paul, 1933 Jun 20 (Box 5, Folder 157)
    - Burroughs, Bryson, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 158)
    - Butcher, Harold, 1939-43, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - Bynner, Witter, 1914-55, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 160-161)
      Includes letters to Bynner from MDL and R. E. F. Larsson, and carbon from Bynner to "Rockwell"
    - "C" General, 1914-55, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 162-167)
    - Cane, Florence, 1927, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 168)
    - Cane, Melville H.
      See: Harcourt, Brace & Company, Box 17, folders 462-466
    - Carb, David, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 169)
    - Carr, Loraine, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 170)
    - Cary, George, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 171)
    - Cary, Seward, 1913-44, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 172)
    - Cary, Walter, 1923, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - Cather, Willa, 1923-42, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 174-176)
      Includes note from MDL
    - Cerf, Bennett
      See: Random House (Firm), Box 29, folder 831
    - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1913 Apr 8 (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - Chávez, Carlos, 1931-50 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Chávez, Dennis, 1936-48 (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Churchill, Judith Chase, 1945-46 (Box 6, Folder 180)
    - Clark, Rose, 1922-36, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 181-186)
    - Clark, Walter, 1946, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 187)
    - Clemens, Cyril, 1938-53 (Box 6, Folder 188)
    - Colefax, Sibyl, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 189)
    - Collier, John, 1916-38, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 190)
      See also: Elizabeth Duncan School, Box 10, folders 289-296
      See also: "H" general, Box 16, folders 433-440
      See also: Native American Indian material, Box 26, folders 745-752
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters of John and Lucy Collier 1913-1917" (leaves 1-54), Box 51, folder 1405
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Misce[l]laneous Letters 1914 (leaves 142-54), Box 52, folder 1406
      See also: Scrapbooks, "Misc. Vol. II," Box 92, folder 2261
    - Collier, Lucy, 1922 Jul (Box 6, Folder 191)
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters of John and Lucy Collier 1913-1917" (leaves 55-60), Box 51, folder 1405
    - Comfort, Jane, 1937-52, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 192-193)
      Includes photographs
    - Comfort, Will Levington, 1914-24, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 194-195)
      Includes carbons from MDL to Comfort and from Comfort to D. H. Lawrence
    - Concha, Eliseo, 1931, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 196)
    - Condé Nast Publications, Inc., 1943 Dec 15 (Box 7, Folder 197)
    - Cook, George Cram, 1914 Mar 13 (Box 7, Folder 198)
    - Cook, Howard, 1928-52, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 199)
      Includes poems
    - Cook, Nilla Cram, 1937 Feb (Box 7, Folder 200)
    - Cornell, Katherine, 1925 May 18 (Box 7, Folder 201)
    - Cosmopolitan, 1933-38, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 202)
      See also: Van Vechten, Carl, Box 35, folders 1020-1028
    - Cothren, [Marion B.?], 1915 Jan 25 (Box 7, Folder 203)
    - Coward McCann, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 204)
    - Craig, Gordon, 1935, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 205)
    - Cramb, Rosemary, 1942 Mar 30 (Box 7, Folder 206)
    - Creel, George
      See: Scrapbooks, "Many Inventions!" Box 90, folder 2259
    - Cristina, Maria, 1929-30 (Box 7, Folder 207)
    - Crockett, Albert Stevens, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 208)
    - Crowley, Aleister, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 209)
    - Crown Publishers, 1949 Oct 4 (Box 7, Folder 210)
    - Cruttwell, Maud, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 211)
    - Curley, John Gee, 1922-23, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 212)
    - Current Opinion, 1915-17, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 213)
    - Curtis Brown Ltd., 1938-45 (Box 7, Folder 214)
      Includes carbons from MDL to Curtis Brown and from Curtis Brown to Cosmopolitan
    - Cutting, Bronson, 1931-35 (Box 7, Folder 215)
    - "D" General, 1912-53, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 216-219)
    - Darrow, Clarence, 1914-15, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 220)
    - Dasburg, Andrew, 1914-53, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 221-223)
      Includes photocopy of letter from MDL
    - Dasburg, Marina, 1934-47, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 224-225)
    - Davey, William, 1941-44, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 226)
    - Davidson, Jo, 1914, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 227)
    - Davidson, Yvonne de Kerstrat, 1913, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 228)
    - Defries, Amelia, 1925, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 229)
    - De Kay, Drake, 1940 Feb 5 (Box 8, Folder 230)
    - Dell, Floyd, 1922, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 231)
    - Dempsey, John J., 1936-45, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 232)
      Includes letters from MDL and carbon enclosures from Thomas Parran and Frank T. Hines
    - Denman, Leslie, 1939, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 233)
    - Detti, Marguerite, 1912-13 (Box 8, Folder 234)
    - Dewey, John, 1930 Jan 28 (Box 8, Folder 235)
    - The Dial, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 236)
      See also: Moore, Marianne, Box 26, folder 724
    - Dial Press, 1944 May 10 (Box 8, Folder 237)
    - Dietrich, Margretta S., 1939-44 (Box 8, Folder 238)
    - Dodge, Edwin Sherrill, 1912-35, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 239-241)
      Includes copies of letters from MDL to ESD and from ESD to "Mrs. Montagne"
      See also: Writings, Autobiographical Writings, "Letters from Hutchins & Neith Hapgood..." (leaves 154-165), Box 51, folder 1404
    - Donahoe, Edward, 1944-52 (Box 8, Folder 242-250)
      Includes letters from Paul Fox and Robert Penn Warren and enclosures
    - Donahoe, Edward, 1952-53 (Box 9, Folder 251-259)
      Includes letters from Tom Mabry, Cedric [Cardigan?], Gordon Kahn and Margaret May
    - Donahoe, Edward, 1953-54, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 260-262)
    - Donaldson, Hildegard, 1938-46, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 263)
    - Donaldson, Midge, 1946, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 264)
    - Donaldson, Norman V., 1946-48 (Box 9, Folder 265)
    - Dorsey, Mattie F., 1934 Feb 28 (Box 9, Folder 266)
    - Doubleday, E. Stillman, 1914, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 267-268)
      Includes carbon manuscript
    - Draper, Muriel, 1912-35, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 269-270)
    - Draper, Paul, [1912?] Nov 17 (Box 10, Folder 271)
    - Dreiser, Theodore, 1938 Apr 19 (Box 10, Folder 272)
    - Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1913 Nov 7 (Box 10, Folder 273)
    - Dudley, Lotus, 1919, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 274)
    - Duell, Sloan & Pearce, 1947-48, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 275-276)
      Includes letters from MDL, carbon of MDL's "Folkways of Artists," and list of Taos painters
      See also: James, Rebecca Salsbury, Box 19, folders 539-541
      See also: Scrapbooks, "History of Taos & Its Artists," Box 85, folder 2254
    - Duncan, Elizabeth, 1914-48, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 277-279)
    - Dunn, Alice, 1938-43, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 280)
    - Dunn, Charles Wesley, 1938-43 (Box 10, Folder 281)
    - Duse, Eleonora, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 282)
    - "E" General, 1914-51, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 283)
    - Eastman, Max, 1913-48, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 284-285)
      Includes carbon of letter from Eastman to Frank Tannenbaum
    - Eaton, Jeannette, 1915, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 286)
    - Ede, H. S. (Harold Stanley), 1932-33, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 287)
    - Edgerly, Mira, 1913-15, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 288)
    - Elizabeth Duncan School, 1914-50, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 289-296)
      Includes correspondence from John Collier, Max Merz, and Eve [Young- Hunter?], 3rd-party correspondence and enclosures
      See also: Duncan, Elizabeth, Box 10, folders 277-279
      See also: Young-Hunter, Eve, Box 38, folders 1113-1116
    - Ellis, Havelock, 1925-27 (Box 10, Folder 297)
    - English, Granville, 1940 Jan 30 (Box 10, Folder 298)
    - Equality, 1940 Jan 10 (Box 10, Folder 299)
    - Ernst, Morris L., 1940-42, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 300)
    - Evans, Alice Henderson (daughter-in-law), 1922-52, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 301-303)
    - Evans, Bonnie (grand-daughter), 1947-54, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 304-308)
      Includes note from MDL to Donald Gallup and drawings
      See also: Evans, Claire, Box 11, folders 309-318
      See also: Evans, Sandy, Box 14, folder 371
    - Evans, Claire Spencer (daughter-in-law), 1932-54, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 309-317)
      Includes copy of letter from Bonnie Evans and photograph
    - Evans, Claire Spencer (daughter-in-law), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 318)
    - Evans, Donald, 1913-14, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 319-320)
      See also: Ficke, Arthur Davison, Box 14, folder 385
    - Evans, Elizabeth Glendower, 1916 Oct 10 (Box 11, Folder 321)
      See also: Woman's Peace Party, Box 38, folder 1102
    - Evans, James Carey, 1919 (Box 11, Folder 322)
      Includes carbon of letter to John Evans
    - Evans, Jim (nephew), 1920 (Box 11, Folder 323)
    - Evans, John (1902-) (son), 1912-25 (Box 12, Folder 324-332)
      Includes enclosures and letters to Evans from MDL, Finchot and Warren, Arthur Brisbane, and Virgil K. Whitaker
      See also: United States Office of Indian Affairs, Box 34, folder 1008
    - Evans, John (1902-) (son), 1926-53 (Box 12, Folder 333-341)
    - Evans, John (1902-) (son), 1954, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 342-350)
    - Evans, John (1902-) (son), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 351-359)
    - Evans, John (1902-) (son), n.d. (Box 14, Folder 360-368)
    - Evans, Nancy (grand-daughter), 1936, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 369)
    - Evans, Natalie Sarah (grand-daughter), 1933-47, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 370)
      Includes drawings
    - Evans, Sandy (grandson), 1941-53, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 371)
    - "F" General, 1913-54, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 372-375)
    - Fairweather, Una, 1929-38, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 376-377)
    - Farrar & Rinehart, 1938-41 (Box 14, Folder 378)
    - Fay, Eliot G., 1952-53 (Box 14, Folder 379)
    - Fechin, Alexandra, 1927-37, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 380)
    - Federation for Child Study, 1915 Nov 3 (Box 14, Folder 381)
    - Ferber, Edna, 1934-36, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 382)
    - Fergusson, Harvey, 1922-23 (Box 14, Folder 383)
    - Feshin, Nikolai Ivanovich, 1933-46, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 384)
      See also: Fechin, Alexandra, Box 14, folder 380
    - Ficke, Arthur Davison, 1913-37 (Box 14, Folder 385)
      Includes manuscript by Donald Evans
    - Field, George H., 1912-17, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 386)
    - Filler, Louis, 1940 Jan 28 (Box 14, Folder 387)
    - Finney, Charity, 1916-34 (Box 14, Folder 388)
    - Fitzgerald, Ch[arles?], 1913-14 (Box 14, Folder 389)
    - Flaherty, Frances H., 1928, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 390)
    - Fletcher, Constance, 1914, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 391)
    - Flint, Ralph, 1925-35, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 392)
    - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, 1914, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 393)
    - Foote, Mary, 1911-53, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 394-399)
    - Foote, William, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 400)
    - Force, Juliana; Clapp, Frederick Mortimer, 1948 May 23 (Box 15, Folder 401)
    - The Forum, 1938 Sep 6 (Box 15, Folder 402)
    - Fox Film Corporation, 1933 Mar 15 (Box 15, Folder 403)
    - Francis, John A., 1914-15 (Box 15, Folder 404)
    - Free Speech League (New York, N.Y.), n.d. (Box 15, Folder 405)
    - Freeman, E. W., 1929-32, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 406)
    - Froes, Heiter Praguer, 1944 Jul 26 (Box 15, Folder 407)
    - Fülöp-Miller, René, 1940 May 23 (Box 15, Folder 408)
    - [Fummis?], Charles T., 1926-27, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 409)
    - "G" General, 1913-52, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 410-413)
    - Gallup, Donald
      See: Lawrence, Frieda von Richtofen, Box 23, folders 632-640
      See: Yale University Library, Box 38, folder 1109
    - Gamio, Manuel, 1930 Dec 8 (Box 15, Folder 414)
    - Gannett, Lewis
      See: New York Herald Tribune, Box 27, folder 766
    - Ganson, Sara Cook
      See: Montague, Sara Cook Ganson, Box 26, folders 721-723
    - Garland, Marie T.
      See: Scrapbooks, "Lawrence," Box 87, 2256
    - Gaynor, Janet, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 415)
      See also: Adrian, Gilbert, Box 1, folders 16-18
    - Gelber, Lilienthal Inc., 1935 (Box 15, Folder 416)
    - General Federation of Women's Clubs, 1915, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 417)
    - Gillmore, Inez Haynes, 1925-33, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 418)
      Includes carbons of correspondence between Gillmore and Edna [Kenton?]
    - Gish, Lillian, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 419)
    - Golden, Eithne, 1943-45, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 420)
    - Golden Gate International Exposition, 1939 Mar 11 (Box 15, Folder 421)
    - Goldman, Emma, 1913-14, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 422)
    - Goodwin, Walter L.
      See: Duell, Sloan & Pearce, Box 10, folders 275-276
    - Goodyear, A. Conger (Anson Conger)
      See: Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.), Box 26, folder 732
    - Goodyear, Mary, 1916-39, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 423)
    - Goyen, Bill, 1949, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 424)
    - Grant Watson, E. L., 1913, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 425)
    - Gray, David, 1932 Oct (Box 15, Folder 426)
    - Gregory, Harold Anthony, 1943-48, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 427)
    - Groves, John Stuart, 1933 Dec 29 (Box 15, Folder 428)
    - Grundy, J. Owen, 1941-43 (Box 15, Folder 429)
    - Gurdjieff, Georges Ivanovitch, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 430)
    - Gutierrez, Ernesto N., 1952 (Box 15, Folder 431)
    - Gutierrez, Undine, 1952-53 (Box 15, Folder 432)
    - "H" General, 1914-52, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 433-440)
      Includes reply from MDL to S. W. Smith, introductory letter from John Collier, accompanying J. Houard letter, and enclosures
    - Haas, Robert Bartlett, 1937 Oct 3 (Box 16, Folder 441)
    - [Hacksner?], Lenny, 1936-37 (Box 16, Folder 442)